

Professional Developer

Phone: (805) 551-0638

Website: www.JohnRussellHarrison.com
Email: JohnRussellHarrison@gmail.com

Address: 415 Erie Ave

Tampa, FL 33606

Summary

Award winning developer with a strong foundation in modern front-end and server technology. DevOps expert with experience in fast prototyping and enterprise level deployments. Comfortable working long hours to organize and coordinate with teams to build out platforms.

Professional Tool Kit

Proficient Coding:

- ✓ Application: ASP.NET, C#, Node.JS, Express.JS, WCF Services
- ✓ Front End: JavaScript, Angular.JS, CSS, HTML5, JQuery, Bootstrap
- ✓ Database: SQL, MongoDB, Stored Procedures

Applications:

- ✓ Bug Tracking: JIRA, CMIS, Change Control
- ✓ Subversion: GIT, Stash, Amazon CodeCommit
- ✓ Design: Adobe Suite (Photoshop/Illustrator), Confluence

Award Winning Projects

vStart Innovation Platform - App Challenge

October 2015

Brought together and managed a development team of new hires. Designed and deployed a platform that was picked up by multiple business units for further development.

Languages: Node.JS, Angular.JS, JADE, Express, Bootstrap and MongoDB

VCOP Timeline - Verizon Ovation Award

April 2014

Oversaw the implementation of a front-end timeline for records within Verizon's change management platform, VCOP. Contributions led to a February release, saving the project from its 'Jeopardy' status in January. Coordinated and released the first major upgrades to the platform since 2008.

Languages: ASP.NET, Bootstrap, CSS, JQuery and C#

Education

University of Southern California

May 2012

B.S. Computer Engineering

Experience

Verizon IT - Member Technical Staff III

July 2012 - Present

Client Account Management _ CFO IT | Tampa, FL (Present)

- → Align business timelines with IT development and drive implementation processes.
- ightarrow Coordinating massive testing effort for Single-Biller Release.

PMO Organization - FiOS New Products | Tampa, FL

- → Managed JIRA Platform for FiOS New Products Organization.
- → Worked launch of FiOS IPTV, a nationwide update to our video platform.

C# Developer - Change Management | Alpharetta, GA

- → Led development launch of a Verizon Ovation Award winning front-end improvement to Verizon's change management tool, VCOP.
- ightarrow Deployed internal websites including the Change Management Portal and Home Page.

Infrastructure Support - Verizon Wireless | Irvine, CA

- → Created a PHP Storage Automation Tool, which saved 27 terabytes of data, valued at \$135,000 in cost savings, through interfacing with numerous internal systems.
- → Assisted with the upgrading, commissioning and decommissioning of servers.

Technical Intern - Cisco

Summer 2011

Engineering/Marketing CO OP - Cypress

Summer 2010

More Proud Projects

PHP Storage Automation Tool

January 2013

Created a system that interfaces with numerous legacy applications to automate the manual work of closing out non-assigned storage requests.

Languages: PHP, SQL, Bootstrap, JavaScript and JQuery

Trouble Ticket Tracking

November 2015

Built a web application to allow comparison of the 30 K records within Verizon's Trouble Ticketing system, CMIS. Automated report reading and comparisons.

Languages: Node.JS, Angular.JS, C#, ASP.NET, WCF Services, SQL and Bootstrap

Email Automation Systems

2013 - Present

Supporting systems which use Excel and templates to generate emails for various organizations to automate their communication.

Languages: Outlook, Excel, C#, ASP.NET, JS, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap

Personal Website

October 2015 - Present

Maintaining a personal website built using modern front-end technologies.

Languages: Express, Bootstrap, Angular.JS, Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator

Please visit JohnRussellHarrison.com for more information. References available on request.